[
    {
        "QuestionNum": "1",
        "Question": "What is the name of the Hobbit that carries the ring most of the way in The Lord of the Rings?",
        "A": "Merry",
        "B": "Frodo",
        "C": "Sam",
        "D": "Pippin",
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "2",
        "Question": "Which wizard accompanied the Fellowship on their travels in the Fellowship of the Ring?",
        "A": "Saruman",
        "B": "Gandalf",
        "C": "Radagast",
        "D": "Tom Bombadil",
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "3",
        "Question": "What is the name of Sauron's tower?",
        "A": "Minas Tirith",
        "B": "Minas Anor",
        "C": "Orthanc",
        "D": "Barad-dûr",
        "Answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "4",
        "Question": "How many members are in the Fellowship?",
        "A": "8",
        "B": "9",
        "C": "6",
        "D": "7",
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "5",
        "Question": "What is the name of the Ent that accompanies Merry and Pippin?",
        "A": "Treebeard",
        "B": "Beechbone",
        "C": "Fimbrethil",
        "D": "Finglas",
        "Answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "6",
        "Question": "Who was the last high king of the Noldor that served in Lindon?",
        "A": "Finrod Felagund",
        "B": "Gil-Galad",
        "C": "Fingolfin",
        "D": "Fëanor",
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "7",
        "Question": "What land did Sauron take for himself and rule from during the Third Age of Middle-Earth?",
        "A": "The Shire",
        "B": "Mordor",
        "C": "Gondor",
        "D": "Rhûn",
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "8",
        "Question": "Who is Shelob's mother?",
        "A": "Ungoliant",
        "B": "Aragog",
        "C": "Morgoth",
        "D": "Éowyn",
        "Answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "9",
        "Question": "What is the name of the older, white and male, tree that gave light to Arda in the Year of the Tree in Tolkien's legendarium?",
        "A": "Laurelin",
        "B": "Telperion",
        "C": "Treebeard",
        "D": "Yavanna",
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "10",
        "Question": "What is the name of the younger, gold and female, tree that gave light to arda in the Year of the Tree in Tolkien's legendarium?",
        "A": "Laurelin",
        "B": "Telperion",
        "C": "Ulmo",
        "D": "Mandos",
        "Answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "11",
        "Question": "Morgoth was the original evil in Tolkien's legendarium. This was a name given to him by Fëanor to mean, 'Black Foe of the World.' What was his original name?",
        "A": "Finwë",
        "B": "Maedhros",
        "C": "Melkor",
        "D": "Tulkas",
        "Answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "12",
        "Question": "Who was the second member of the Fellowship to die during the quest to destroy the One Ring?",
        "A": "Gandalf",
        "B": "Boromir",
        "C": "Gimli",
        "D": "Aragorn",
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "13",
        "Question": "Mount Doom is the extremely popular volcano where the One Ring was created, and later destroyed. What is the Sindarin translation?",
        "A": "Melon",
        "B": "Orodruin",
        "C": "Ephel Dúath",
        "D": "Emyn Muil",
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "14",
        "Question": "There is a set of twin statues that the Fellowship sail by on their quest. What is the name of these statues?",
        "A": "Argonath",
        "B": "Enedwaith",
        "C": "Minas Ithil",
        "D": "Oromë",
        "Answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "15",
        "Question": "Frodo and Sam, after leaving the rest of the Fellowship, encounter a creature. What is the name of this creature?",
        "A": "Bilbo",
        "B": "Fatty Bolger",
        "C": "Gollum",
        "D": "Déagol",
        "Answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "16",
        "Question": "Sauron created many rings beyond his One Ring. among all of them, he created 9 for men. What did these men come to be known?",
        "A": "Haradrim",
        "B": "Easterlings",
        "C": "Rohirrim",
        "D": "Nazgûl",
        "Answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "17",
        "Question": "Who is the god-like character in Tolkien's legendarium?",
        "A": "Manwë",
        "B": "Eru Ilúvatar",
        "C": "Aulë",
        "D": "Ulmo",
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "18",
        "Question": "Which Valar created the dwarves in Tolkien's legendarium?",
        "A": "Eru Ilúvatar",
        "B": "Aulë",
        "C": "Nienna",
        "D": "Varda",
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "19",
        "Question": "Morgoth was the strongest of the Valar before his downfall into darkness. Who then, after Morgoth, became the strongest of the Valar to be the mouth for Eru Ilúvatar?",
        "A": "Estë",
        "B": "Vairë",
        "C": "Mandos",
        "D": "Manwë",
        "Answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "QuestionNum": "20",
        "Question": "There was a love story that was deeply personal to Tolkien. What two characters are in this story?",
        "A": "Aragorn & Arwen",
        "B": "Beren & Lúthien",
        "C": "Faramir & Éowyn",
        "D": "Samwise & Rosie",
        "Answer": "B"
    }
]